So then you know it's doing
>> that's what I need to know. Okay.
Unicorn unicorn unic code Kelvin. Dang
it guys. Do not make a meme in freaking
Discord about unicorn. Please t-shirt
>> dude. Shut up.
>> Best part of hacking when you can just
you know critical think.
Yeah,
>> dude.
[Music]
>> All right, hackers. Here's the deal.
Before you skip forward, give me like
two seconds to give you a takeaway.
Okay, here it is. Threat Locker Detect
is the best EDR around. They have a ton
of tool integrations. The alerts are
high signal, so you're not swimming in a
bunch of garbage, and both alerting and
remediation actions are super
customizable. It's definitely the one
you want. Okay, that's it. Skip forward
if you must, but I do feel like you
should know why I think that, right?
Well, we've talked a lot about the
threat locker suite, and frankly,
they're the best implemented tools
around from a technical perspective.
With this EDR, they're focusing a lot on
customization and high signal stuff like
PowerShell activity, log deletion,
sketchy RDP sessions, stuff that I have
wished many times EDRs were not uh
detecting actively. Okay. Um, and while
it does work out of the box, it also
gives you the, the experienced purple
teamer, the tools you need to implement
custom logic to lock hackers out of your
network at the first sign of trouble,
that trouble is the trouble that you are
most qualified to recognize. So, they're
equipping you to to deal with it right
away. Um, the definitely the ones you
guys want to go with if you're looking
for a new EDR tool. All right, that's
it. Let's go back to the show.
>> All right, Ryan, dude, come here, man.
Thank you so much for today. We I just
had a fantastic day up in Restston with
Ryan Barnett. Um and we are here at the
Aquami offices after battling our
computer systems for a while to try to
get the recording equipment in place.
Finally able to record the episode. Um
Ryan, dude, I'm looking at this doc. You
prepped a lot. I so appreciate that.
>> Well, yeah.
>> You know, I listen to the podcast as you
well know and I love all the stories,
especially war stories and all that
stuff. And so once you told me the
dates, I was like, "Okay, I got time.
Let let me go through the files here and
stuff I thought would be interesting for
everybody and for us to talk about."
>> Dude, I'm very excited. I think it's
going to be a new kind of episode. You
know, a lot of times we have people that
are actively hunting in the bug bounty
scene and you are on the receiving side
of a lot of these reports, right? And
and you see them what's coming through
the Akami bug bounty queue and then you
also see the traffic that's happening um
live in the Akami network. So um very
exciting stuff. But before we get into
too much of the details, you got to cut
your teeth with a bounty with with a
with a bug that you found. Okay. Yeah.
Um and and we do have a little bit of a
twist on this for for you today because
there there's a bug that you found here,
but there's also uh a couple bugs that
you've triaged that you were excited
about. So um let's uh let's do a a proof
proof of concept here. Let's uh PC or
GTFO and uh tell me tell me what you
got. Um so the first one was interesting
um because it was actually an accidental
finding which sometimes that happens
right you're using an app.
>> Yeah.
>> So this was a number of years ago but I
was using uh online uh blogging software
typad
>> I'm in the middle of talking about some
research right on cross-sight scripting.
I'm typing up. So I'm in the editor and
out of nowhere it popped up redirected
to a third party website.
>> Oh man.
>> And of course my spidey sense is like
wait what's going on? refresh. Doing it
again happens again. Then I stopped and
I looked at where it was redirecting me
to and I said, "Whoa, whoa, whoa." This
was from a blog post I did a week ago. I
said, "Wait a second." So, the short of
this is I had to get out some tools to
look at what was going on and see where
my traffic was going. So, what happened
was a week before I did a blog post
talking about cross-sight scripting
>> and there were cross-ite scripting tags
that were in uh user agent headers. So
I'm putting it into the blog and when I
put it in the blog I made sure the HTML
entity and code don't
I did everything by the book and so uh
the problem was what was interesting
once I tracked this down was in Typad
they have all these plugins and what
they want to do is as you're typing as
an editor it would show you oh we see
the content you're doing here are some
related posts if you want to cross link
>> okay
>> so it cross link with one of my former
posts well what happens is this third
party and It's fixed. So obviously so I
can say it was called semant.
>> They had uh API clients. They come and
scrape your content.
>> When they scraped it, it was the
rendered content.
>> So as I'm typing and they said, "Oh, we
have a suggestion here. It comes back in
JSON nonHTML entity encoded."
>> Ah,
>> and then the other key piece was the
plugin. When it got that JSON, it
wrapped it. It treated as HTML.
So popped. And I was like, ah crap. So
two things. Number one, vulnerability
disclosure. I worked with them. They
fixed it.
>> I guess that's one advantage of the kind
of SAS platforms that they don't have to
give patches to people. They just fixed
it. Boom. Done
>> across the board.
>> Yeah. Treat as text. It was fixed.
>> Uh but for me
>> that day forward, I do pictures of
exploit code. I don't do text. You never
know. There could be an API. And today
it's like even worse, right? with all
these API uh AI agents crawling and you
don't know what they're doing with your
data or how they make
>> I mean even with pictures nowadays
sometimes something will OCR it you know
and like true but uh but yeah I mean I I
definitely I think that's definitely the
safest way to go but then me for me when
I'm trying to hack something right on
the other side of the board I'm like oh
let me copy this no it's a picture you
know I'm like oh
>> gez it's a balance it but that showed me
it's like you don't know who's coming to
grab that content so that was very
tricky Absolutely, man. And and I think
one of the unique things that we've
discussed time and time again is like
how much you see the way that the
internet is connected internet is
connected from across all of these
different, you know, pieces, right? You
know, somebody puts in a piece of data
here and somehow it ends up, you know,
in your client's log somehow and it's
causing a problem somewhere, right?
Yeah.
>> Um
>> all the the blind stuff, right? You put
it in, it'll pop out. Who knows? I can't
imagine how many websites have alert
one, you know, just like popping up on
the back end, you know, and they're
like, "Oh, that's kind of funky." But
nobody like took the time to do
>> a blind XSS payload or something like
that.
>> Yeah. Well, tons of our customers with
SIMs and looking at logs.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's a
>> Yeah. Custom stuff in the Sims as well.
You know, it can it can pop anywhere.
>> Um, okay. So, you got you got chat
scatter and you got abusing thirdparty
analytics. Yeah. Where are we going?
>> Um, well, we can cover both. They're
fast again. So these were once I
triaged. So cross- sight scripting
problem.
>> Uh once it comes through um you know
whoever was doing the bug bounty program
who's our customer back to us.
>> So these two different ones uh one
looking at it was um abusing some
JavaScript analytic code.
>> Okay.
>> So this fits in with a bunch of hunters
that you got to look and say okay what
are all these URLs JavaScript's calling
up? Look at these endpoints. What are
they doing? And here I was actually
looking through the code
>> because what they figured out was um
there was a function in the JavaScript
that was pulled up where it was talking
about a mod configuration override set
to true.
>> Oh jeez.
>> So the attacker just puts it in a query
string. So instead of passing in
JavaScript passed it in a query string
and then it's this long kind of
serialized uh configuration to say oh
turn it on and by the way here's a
script which is my hacker script which
pulled it up. But like from our
perspective, those aren't normal
payloads that we see. Yeah.
>> So it's really abusing that default
config. Yeah.
>> Uh the short one there is of course we
helped the customer to tell them what
was going on.
>> You know, we updated their configs.
>> Um but the vendor silently fixed it.
>> Of course, you're back to the SAS
platform though. They just went and
tweaked it.
>> Um so that's where way back saves you,
of course, because I I can go back and
say this is what it was,
>> right? It was like this.
>> It was like this. Um and then the the
last one uh called it chat scatter. Um
>> again working with a customer um there
was some cross-ite scripting stuff
coming in once I was kind of triaging
looking at it cross-ite scripting coming
in a certain query string parameter but
the parameter was an entire long
payload. It was a URI
>> from not our customer site third party
site.
>> So I had to start tracing it back. So
you go to what that other site was and
looking through and then kind of tie
back how does this relate to our
customer. It was a chat widget. So you
get to that page. Hey popup. Can we help
you? We want to talk to you. So what's
interesting is
>> those are everywhere nowadays too.
>> Everything right? They pop up. But so
again for bug hunters knowing what
happens there. As soon as you load that
in your browser it can be making backend
API calls and what it was doing is
grabbing the entire URI and beaconing to
our customer. So what I was seeing was
telemetry, this back scatter or chat
scatter of bug hunters and real
attackers attacking crossite scripting
and it immediately sends it off to us
and we see it. So they're not attacking
our customer but we saw
>> so for me interesting conversation sorry
with our customer
>> smack the mic. Yeah I do it all the time
man
>> uh with our customer to say look you do
not have a vulnerability
>> your customers using your software are
being attacked and I did confirm some of
the crossite scripting that worked.
Yeah.
>> And I said, "You might want to tell
them."
>> Yeah.
>> But there's an interesting situation.
These are smaller companies who don't
have security teams and they can
misinterpret and say, "Well, this is
because of your software." So,
>> it was up to them. I don't know who all
they reached out to, but we had to,
>> you know, get pass on the information as
a good net citizen and say, "You may
want to tell those."
>> Well, I think something, you know, you
see a lot of client side stuff by nature
of what you're doing there. And and I
think that analytics um those analytics
>> uh providers, you know, they're
integrate. I mean, sometimes you go into
some of these sites and they've got like
10 of them, right? And some of the the
ones that are I mean, not to say that
there isn't a vulnerability out there
and like Google Tag Manager or
something. I'm sure there is somebody
can find, not me. Um but, you know, in
some of these other sketchy analytics
plugins, there are a lot of weird
configuration overrides. Why are you
parsing this URL parameter? you know,
like um I'll never forget I was at a
live hacking event and there was this
piece of scope that everybody struggled
with because there just wasn't very much
there, right? There were like there's
not a lot of functionality. We can't
really do anything. And somebody ended
up finding like a beautiful DOMXS that
affected every single page of that site
because of this weird analytics thing
that they found.
>> And uh it was just taking a a URL
parameter and and like you said,
importing a JavaScript file. So yeah, um
they they're out there, they exist,
>> and it's it's a challenge because that's
usually a totally different team than
the app team and they're kind of forcing
in certain analytics stuff for business.
>> Yeah. For marketing analytics. Yeah.
Yeah. Absolutely. It's and and they
probably don't necessarily go through
the same vendor vetting as like some of
the other um uh places do. And and
actually come to think of it, I think
I've mentioned this on the pod a couple
times, but um I'm thinking about a
specific target where um you know is a
very high security target that has to be
by nature of their industry. Um and
yeah, you know, we spent so much time
poking at the client side of this thing.
And then of course the hole is in the
third party software that they just kind
of threw in there as like let me add
this chatbot, let me add this analytics,
right? Yeah. Um and we ended up popping
a bunch of because of that vulnerable
analytics uh piece.
>> Yeah. And for crazy, man.
>> Other folks you've had on the show.
>> Yeah.
>> We were just talking about loopin. Yeah.
Like supply chain. That's all this stuff
and they're adding stuff in. Yeah. Yeah.
Different vectors on how
>> lots of different stuff there. Okay. So,
the meat of the Okay, let me let me back
up. I always I always get tempted, you
know, because we get in the in the vibe
from the the vol. I I always forget to
come back to the introduction. And then
when I do, my dad always messages me and
he's like, Justin, you forgot to
introduce. And I'm like, why are you
watching this 20 minutes in anyway, Dad?
you don't understand anything that's
happening. But shout out to dad. Thank
you for watching episodes and keeping me
um uh in line with that. Um so with
that, I'll I'll back up. Guys, this is
Ryan Barnett. He's uh an OG in the
Defender space. And actually, we found
out recently that I bought your book
back in 2017 when I was first learning
how to hack. I was like, uh I got to get
this, you know, application defenders
cookbook and uh and you know, try to
like figure out exactly what what I'm up
against here. Right.
>> Um and I went to my Amazon history and
it bought in 2017. I was like, "No way.
That's my boy Ryan."
>> Perfect.
>> Um so thank you for the the content you
put out. Um really appreciate that. And
um yeah, I mean your your track record
speaks for speaks for itself. You're at
Mod Security. You're at uh Akami now as
a as a principal researcher for like 10
years.
>> A decade.
>> Wow. Dude. And and and we were at lunch
before this. We went out and grabbed
lunch before and I was just telling him
like that's inspiring
>> because you know so many you know we
really value highly technical people
here on the podcast and um you know so
many people especially in in a you know
bigger company where it would be easy to
go up the up the ladder a little bit you
know uh it takes a lot of grit to stick
to uh you know you know research
position it is
>> it's a passion I love research
>> and you you did you did a lot of it for
a long time
>> we're also joking about persistence
Yeah.
>> Both for bug hunters and also on the
defensive side, persistence is key.
>> Yeah, absolutely, man. Well, um you
know, obviously you're working with
Aami. Um
>> the gut feeling when we hear the word
aami is terror, you know, from the from
the bug bounty hunter. Like, ah [__]
did I just get my whole IP burned again?
Like, why can't I get my cross-ite
scripting payload through? Um, so I
think you know one of the things we had
here in in the doc as far as discussion
goes is this bug bounty versus w like
how do we balance these two things uh in
the industry and you know sometimes it
is like we're juxtaposed you know it's
like we're it's like we're up against
each other here you know um but we often
forget that we're all on the same team
so um I guess what what are some things
you want hackers to know about that that
dynamic um of you We're as bug asbug
bounty hunters. We're on the same team,
but we're going up against you guys all
the time.
>> Yeah. So, the a couple different kind of
discussion points and we can take
different angles.
>> Um, one of the main one we always start
with is our customers
>> and particularly when they're working in
bug bounty, it's like what is their main
goal?
>> Now, everybody intuitively jumps to
well-defined bones. That's that's why
you do bug bounty, which it is. uh but
it's not every use case or some start
there and they move to a different use
case. So
>> you can look at it as vulnerability
enumeration. If that's their main goal,
>> then they want bug hunters to find the
bugs. So then if we're in the middle
there, how do they want us to treat the
traffic?
>> Right? So part of that is just
understanding what the customers want
and what their goal is. So in that
scenario, if that's their goal, we need
to figure out ways to allow bug hunters
to get by what we're doing. Just olay,
let you through.
>> So there's ways they can do that for
commercial scanning companies, right?
>> Okay. Okay. I like where this is going,
Ryan. Okay.
>> Yes. Uh but that's because they have
registered IP space, right? Right. So
it's like, oh, you're Qualis, your White
Hat, your Verarica, your whoever. Um, we
know your IPs and it's easy in the
product to do a bypass list. So, if
you're coming from this trusted space,
okay, you can get through.
>> Sure.
>> Um, as everybody knows who's listening
to this,
>> you can't use your IP, right? That's
ephemeral.
>> Yeah.
>> And you sometimes have to hop and go
around. So, there's really not a good
mechanism to let somebody go through if
they wanted to.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, the the other category is that we
have of customers are it's not just
about finding vans. It is, but there's a
a matter of exploitivity of it. Like we
have to prove
>> that you can get to this. And that's
where they want W to act like normal and
treat bug hunters like they would
anybody else and do whatever you're
going to do. Lock that request, mess
with the IP, do like do whatever. Um,
it's very interesting. We had
conversations with some of these
customers to understand like, oh, okay,
that's interesting. Uh, but they want to
do attacker simulation.
>> Yeah. and and they want it to be as as
real world, you know, right? And yeah,
it's a balance
>> because then they can prove this is
exploitable
>> and there's an issue with the WAT
blocking it because if they get to that,
there's Wack bypass.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it it's a matter of them figuring
out priority because they may have a
list of things that they found
internally, you know, SAS and all these
other things and they're like, "Okay, we
have this pile of things we have to fix.
Which ones do we do first?"
>> Oh, w's helping us with some coverage
here. Let's delay that a week or so. But
if you prove bug hunters can get to it,
bypass here, oh crap,
>> real threat actors can do that. Now we
have to bump you up the size. becomes
and and I mean that's what all of
security is right there's always
improvements that need to be made
somewhere in the system right you know
and so that's a good point you know if
you are able to bypass the w
>> uh it helps with the whole triaging of
issues right triage in a different sense
you know figure assigning the the
severity and the priority of these of
these you know various things you need
to address in your security program
right
>> um
>> dude I just I hate it a little bit
though like like come on like you know I
can bypass this Ryan and I can't I just
>> I'm spending so much time.
>> Yeah. You know,
>> so there's a number of things too that
we talked about there on
>> from an external perspective, people see
WFT that are really a lot of separate
products
>> tied together. We have things that look
for just how fast people are going and
the customers can figure out those are
controls.
>> Yep.
>> Familiar with that one.
>> Yeah, exactly. And you're going to get
blocked for a little while. Then there's
client reputation and that's the biggest
thorn for the bug hunters. Yes, it is
>> because it's a little it's more
persistent. Um, it doesn't have to be
just the website you're interacting with
where you were bug hunting because now
Okami is giving that IP a global score.
Then other people who have client
reputation can choose to use that score.
It's not W blocking you. It's W saying,
"Hey, here's the score." And then the
customer can choose what they want to
do. And some people want to get
aggressive and say, "You've attacked
another customer. I don't want you to
attack me and and we blocked you there."
>> Yeah. Yeah, dude. It's that's a pain and
that's what uh there's always like um
there's like a little meme that goes
around in the bug bounty community of
like oh you know you're hacking you're
hacking all of a sudden you know your
wife in the other room is like Justin
why can't I get on you know whatever
website I'm like
I'm like ah dang it what did I do
>> yeah so
>> that's an issue
>> it is it is and and I think there's but
I mean like you said there's
there's two sides of this of of a same
coin, right? You know, we do want to try
to show what is
>> actually exploitable live, you know, and
at the end of the at the end of the day,
I think that's probably the thing that
aligns best with the bug bounty
methodology, right? The PC or GTFO
world, right?
>> Um,
>> but man, it would be nice to get get
around it sometimes. And and you asked
me an interesting question over launch.
you said, "Hey, Justin, would you would
you rather have some way to bypass
Okami, right?" And and like say we did
like some uh you know, certificate based
authentication and and we were able to
get, you know, trusted testers pass,
>> right?
>> Uh and take a lower bounty or or would
you rather just PC or GTFO it? And I'm
like, "Oh,
>> what's option C?"
>> Yeah. Exactly. Right.
>> Yeah. But it the reason why that comes
up again a lot of bug hunters maybe
don't have the same conversations we do
with our customers right
>> and it's for them to understand it was
that second category we talked about
that if they're doing threat actor
simulation
>> um as not not the primary it's always
about loans but that aspect they may be
um setting their bounties in accordance
with that
>> that it is raising your cost
>> you know yeah there's a chance for a
dupe yeah you gota go through different
VPS like you have to do extra work, but
you're getting this amount.
>> So, yeah. I don't know. That's a a
question for every boat hunter to have
to decide for themselves. Would you take
door number one?
>> Oh, no. It's painful, man. And and I do
like the way you've broken it down here.
I'll just repeat this back for the
listener. You know,
>> um there there are two two organ two
types of organizations really. One that
prioritize vulnerability enumeration,
right? That's, you know, bug bounty
hunters being able to say, "Hey, there
is a vulnerability here, but the WFT is
just a thorn in my side. you know, if I
spend two hours, I can bypass it, but
you'd rather me spend time enumerating
other vulnerabilities, right? That sort
of organization would prioritize that
sort of uh behavior. And then there's
the prevention of exploitation attempts,
right? Uh types of organizations where
they really just want PC or GTFO and let
me, you know, assign severity and triage
these issues. So, it's it's a very
interesting um you know, description of
the industry that you've set up and I
think it's very accurate.
>> Yeah.
>> Um very cool, man. Uh there's a lot of
things that I I would love to I would
love to get to here. So I think the next
one that we'll hop into is this whole
concept of of virtual patching, right?
Um right where
>> the W is being used to wall off specific
endpoints as as zero days, you know,
come out and and sometimes it's a
it's something that will solve the
problem. Sometimes there's, you know,
ways you can path traverse around it and
stuff like that. Um yeah, how much of
this how much of this is your main focus
at Okami like and and how have you seen
customers implement this effectively?
>> Um yeah, so two levels. The the real key
here, virtual patching as a term
sometimes people really don't like.
>> Oh, really?
>> And I Yeah, and I understand why.
>> And really this falls in the same bucket
we always everybody talks about. If an
organization is deciding not to actually
fix code and do anything else, you're
like,
>> "Yeah,
>> you sure?"
>> Yeah.
>> So, a virtual patch, some people can
misconrue, oh, it's patched. It's like,
no, the the code's not patched. And so,
one of
>> you should rebrand it temporary virtual
patch, you know, like,
>> yeah, that but that's a key thing. It
should be temporary. Yeah. Give you time
to fix the code, right? Um so anyways
the key here is how WAPs typically work
out of the box as attack detection
systems. They look for bad stuff coming
in right
>> and another thing about coming on the
pod talking with you and thinking about
meta discussions like uh ws live in a
sourc's world
>> bug hunters live in a sinks world.
>> Yeah
>> right and
>> that is a good that is a good line Ryan.
That is a good put put that in a short
put that in a short team.
>> Yeah, it's true because they're
different views. They're all part of the
process. Um and so we're looking at data
coming in attacks. Another way I talk
like in the industry with our customers,
>> they're used to like MITER and CWE
discussions. WS we live in a
>> kek
>> discussion
>> you know you have to make those
correlations. So here, think of W as a
tool, really the paradigm changes is
once a vulnerability is known. Like when
traffic's just going and people put a W
in front and we have our default stuff
there, sure, we can see a lot of bad
stuff in whack-a-ole, we don't know if
where, when there's a VO. Now if they
can signal to us, oh we know there's a
vul here because we get a bug bounty
report,
>> they do pentest, they do code review,
>> then think of w as a tool
>> to implement some sort of mitigation to,
you know, reduce risk, right? U the
other one we talked about is like uh
SharePoint stuff that just comes out.
Exactly.
>> It's the same discussion. It's just we
didn't get that from a customer. We got
it from Microsoft third party. But oh,
vulnerability intelligence, custom
logic, quasi virtual patch. The the key
here too, like you were saying, how good
is it to do that and how long like
what's the halflife of a virtual patch
>> is how you're choosing what logic to put
in still if you're still trying to
negative security stuff that's not as
good.
>> It's tricky though to figure out what
should the payload be. Like we'd love to
do positive security. We don't know the
app necessarily. So, it's key on the
vulnerability details to really figure
out how to do that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Two two directions I'd like
to go with that one. I want to go back
to the the sources and syncs world. So,
we'll we'll um
>> we'll we'll circle back around to that.
But, you know, staying on topic of of
virtual patching. There are scenarios
though when you're standing up a third
party software and that third party
software Yeah. doesn't have, you know,
you don't have the ability to patch that
live, you know, code and and you know,
you can put a in front of it and wall
off certain endpoints, but then, you
know, that's pretty much the extent of
what you can do until the vendor
patches, right?
>> And then, you know, this this is kind of
where these virtual patches become a
little bit more of a permanent solution,
right? If you cannot get that that
software to to patch. Um, so there
there's been a couple vulnerabilities
that I found in the past where, you
know, people are abusing um the WTF to
just see like, okay, well, you can't
access slashdebug anymore, you know, but
but really, you know, there's path
traversals, there's um other ways of
accessing those endpoints, maybe method
overrides or whatever, um or path
overrides,
>> uh that you can utilize to get at them.
So, it's a tricky balance between that,
right?
>> Yeah, it's another thing we talked
about, maybe we'll loop back to it. It's
the whole hacking resistance discussion.
Yeah,
>> because whatever,
>> this is a really good point.
>> Yeah. Whatever
security logic you're putting in,
>> I'm going to grab my notebook really
quick. Keep going.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> You know, whatever security logic you're
putting in, it's a question of like how
strong is that against what type of
attacks to do evasions, right? To get
around it, like you were mentioning.
>> Um,
a lot of these two depend on what's the
category of the problem. Mhm.
>> Um sometimes there's discussions, oh we
found this problem and quote unquote is
this waffable like can we do something?
It's like that's more of an off problem,
>> you know, access control off like those
are things that when you have a third
party system, we don't have the
knowledge or the insights and to know
exactly what should be done there,
right? So it's not that a WAT can fix
everything, but some stuff would fit in
there. Nice. Yeah. Uh, so yeah, hacking
resistance. It's like, okay, we think
that this would hold up, but if you have
a persistent
>> Yeah.
>> attacker that's banging, banging,
banging, who knows how long that this
can hold up, right?
>> And it's a good way to simulate that in
the bug bounty world, right? Like, you
know, we we are persistent because we're
motivated actors, you know, because
we're getting motivation from the money
and and you know, just like APS are
getting motivation from whatever they're
getting motivation from. So, I think it
is a I think it is a cool a cool
simulation and and um definitely there's
this world in which having a W in front
of your assets makes you that much more
annoying to hack where the where the
hacker will just go hack something
that's less annoying to hack, you know,
>> potentially whether it's real thread
actors that like you said, oh, here's
the new CVE of the day.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't care if it's this company or
that company. I just want to upload my
web shell.
>> Exactly.
>> They'll just move on.
>> You're you're weeding out all your
botnet. you know, your ransomware actors
there.
>> There's a lot of noise that you can just
Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's good. Um, swinging back
around to your quote saying that, you
know, laughs live in the source world
and hackers kind of live in the sync
world or at least the connection world
between the two.
>> Um, I think that's super pivotal for uh,
bug bounty hunters to understand. And
now we get to do this segment, Ryan,
where I'm not sure how this is going to
be for you as an Aquami employee, but um
I kind of wanted to talk about what
seems to me to be an unfixable problem
in the W world,
>> which is that
>> um you don't know, you know, what's
going to happen on the on the flip side
of your W, right, on on on the back end.
And so, um you know, you're you have to
make assumptions that that especially in
the XSS world, makes it very very hard,
especially if you're doing contextaware.
>> Yeah. um you know uh blocking y
>> it makes it very difficult for a w to
perform properly. So the the example
that I that I'll often give is this.
Let's say I've got an image tag. image
tags need to be able to flow flow
through the WFT as a part of like you
know user supplied input um you know
it's very common um and and maybe you
know like an attribute a non-malicious
attribute such as X
>> is also allowed right and so let's say
you do something like this X equals
double quote right and then you do
percent 22 and X equals double quote
percent 22 you're inside of the HTML
attribute context right
>> um and then you know you can put
anything inside of that X attribute and
it's not going to be malicious, right?
Um, but so so the, you know, the the W
thinks, okay, you know, now we're inside
of this X attribute. So if I have
something, you know, slash on error
equals alert one,
>> right?
>> And then double quote again, right?
That's all just a part of the X
attribute, but really the back end is
decoding that percent 22 or the percent
2522, right?
>> And and the the mis and sometimes it's
it's inverse, right? Sometimes the W
will be smart about it and say, "Okay,
well, I know that that percent 22 is
also a double quote, so I'm going to
decode that." Well, then you can flip it
on its head, you know, and and say,
"Okay, well, now you think that I'm not
in an an attribute, but I am in an
attribute, right?" And so and so there's
lots of ways that you can sort of flip
that on its head. Um, and I know you've
seen that problem before. Oh, yeah. Like
>> just yesterday.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'm not kidding.
>> Yeah. Oh, geez. Um, I mean, is there is
there some sort of solution to this? Uh,
or is this just something that you guys
are going to have to continue playing a
whack-a-ole game with?
>> Um, a combination. Yeah. Of it.
>> Um, getting back to the whole
whack-a-ole and how we were joking
before where it's like, okay, I've been
doing now 20 years.
>> Took too long.
And at Black Hat,
can't remember, uh, 2011, I gave a talk
called cross- sight scripting street
fight,
>> dude.
>> And you can you can find it. I think
it'll probably be in show notes. I think
it's in our thing.
>> Yeah.
>> So, the idea was going through all these
stages of W. What do I try and do? Let
me try this.
>> But then the bug hunter attacker does
this. Crap. That doesn't work. Let me
try this.
>> Here's the evasion for that. And it's
the chess game. back and forth, back and
forth, regular. So,
>> there's always blacklisting whack-a-ole
approach because you can do that.
>> The question is how much coverage are
you getting, right? Yeah. and then these
evasions um ultimately where I am today
personally understanding the limits
because we live in a source world and
what we're looking at the big X factor
for us or or what do I want to say
challenges are
>> the black box behind us and it's not
just the customer app
>> if you think about what we what we're
tasked with right sorry as as defenders
>> of it can be going to some application
tier
ESP, Java, Page, like whatever
>> can do all sorts of decodings
potentially.
>> It could go into databases. They may do
something and then something different
when they pull it out to use it. But
then also what you just said, think
about browsers.
>> Yeah.
>> And then we have to layer as well. So, a
a common thing that with the researchers
I work with and we talk about this and
uh there's also a funny situation again
this kind of cross-pollination of of us
attackers and defenders. We hire a lot
of bug hunters. Yeah. On the team
>> and exactly and we kind of joke when
they come in, we said, "Look, we we
brought you because it's the whole kind
of know your enemy, so to speak, and how
to attack."
>> But then I always throw out the uh Star
Wars Yoda line. I said, "You must
unlearn what you have learned."
>> And so,
>> Ryan, dude, I gota I got to work with
you, man. Like, this is like amazing.
Whoever gets that job, I'm jealous of
you to work with Ryan.
>> So, what we're thinking about here, and
this is a common phrase that we have to
use, is can we as a do customizations
for your Snowflake app because you want
us to help you protect it? Absolutely.
Outside of that, it's best size fits
most. M
>> we have to figure out okay what can we
do that will work across every single
company uh customer and scale and so a
lot of times what you get into is
between the app tier database web
browser or whatever who's going to
decode what
>> is it going to decode once twice three
times
>> mutations yeah it's
>> the issue we saw yesterday
>> data came in a bunch of stuff was
encoded uh up to three times in certain
parts
>> but then by the time it made it into the
sync,
the thing that was decoded three times
was fully decoded. Other stuff was not
touched, wasn't even decoded once. So,
>> we're in a very tough position to match
up decodings.
>> Um, so yeah, it's a constant battle uh
to figure out how much to do, how much
not to do,
>> and you just have to tackle it from
different angles of detection.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And and one of the and
I I just wanted to mention this for the
listener because I I kind of uh sort of
>> said a lot of code a second ago was one
of the interesting things about HTML
attributes is
>> if you if you start an HTML attribute
with a double quote obviously that
double quote becomes the encapsulating
you know piece for that HTML attribute.
But if you start the double quote with
the the actual text percent 22, then
there's no there's no encapsulating
attribute, right? And you can, you know,
a space will terminate that ht html
attribute. So So I, you know, the
>> there's so many tricks you can do where
it's like, okay, we're going to put a
double quote at the beginning of this a
this attribute, right? Right. Encoded as
percent 22. and the W has to think,
okay, well, I think that's a double
quote, which makes this this a quoted
HTML attribute. But actually, if they're
not decoding it, then it's not a quoted,
it's an unqued, and there's different
terminators,
>> right? So, it's like there's there's so
many layers to that. Um, and it's it's a
very tricky very tricky problem.
>> Yeah, definitely. Another key thing I
always say is, well, it depends. It
always depends on the exact context.
Yeah.
>> Um, some other phrases I've used in the
past which I think are relevant here.
>> Yeah. And we're in a world of artificial
intelligence. I go old school again.
>> For those people who know Marcus Rain
from a long time ago, he had artificial
ignorance
>> and it's a totally different approach
because when you know certain things
that you already know about, you filter
those out. Anything left over. So we try
and take multi- approaches to this
because it's very hard to get the
context right
>> because we're not in the syncs.
>> Yeah.
>> So we don't really know where job you're
doing, Ryan. It's hard, man. So
>> yeah. All I can say is multi-dimensional
detections of ways to try and detect
this because you try and do certain
things in context. If that doesn't work,
you take a step back and you look more
general and you catch a lot of those
that get by the other one.
>> So, let me ask you this. You know, this
this situation that I described with
like the HTML attributes that is
something that um affects context aware,
right? Right. And I'm wondering, you
know, how far you can get in your
opinion with just like, you know, reaxes
or like, you know, blacklists or or
really, you know, at the end of the day,
it's going to be very hard if to get
anything through if you're allowing or
to to prevent everything from getting
through if you're allowing less than and
a, you know, an alphabet character,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> Um, that's kind of where it kind of
reduces down to, I think, in a in a big
way. Yeah. Another
>> So maybe there's a reax for that. You
know,
>> reax serves a purpose. Yeah.
>> And I I'm forgetting off the top of my
head, Chsky, whatever model
>> that's like you have reax, but you have
a higher level grammar. We can't define
that higher level with. So reax serves a
purpose, but we realize the limitations,
but
>> yeah,
>> it serves a purpose because it's fast.
>> You know, you can iterate and do stuff
quickly, but we have other ways to to
look at that data.
>> Going back to what you were saying,
especially on client side.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um
I did some things in the past. I think
we had talked about mod security. We had
these cross-ite scripting challenges
where and I said it in a cross- sight
scripting street fight presentation
that's like
>> this is a browser problem. It's like
yeah the app's not properly encoding or
output you know encoding escaping data
but ultimately the problem's in the
browser. Mhm.
>> So there are situations, for example,
and this is I think there's some stuff
in the in the doc where some of our
customers really want to get into things
like content security policy or pushing
something like uh
>> DOM purify.
>> Yeah,
>> we can do that from the edge.
>> We can dynamically modify data on the
way out because we have separate
products that do different things
>> and we can dynamically put DOM purify
it. So there's all sorts of other things
because I'm like look like you said
there's a limit to what you can do with
sources.
>> So for our customers that want to get
more advanced say okay we can help you
and dynamically put that in. Um so I
don't know it's like more it's a
question of what is
>> W
and where does it end?
>> What is w
it it goes to what you are going to talk
about in a minute as well here with
regards to unicorn normalization. um
this order of operations, right? Like
because if we put DOM purify, I'm sure
you know, but if we put DOM purify at
the edge,
>> if there's any modification of that data
post DOM purification, you know, uh then
it's it's going to affect the integrity
of the work that DOM purify does.
>> Sure.
>> And if you see any, you know, unencoding
or anything like that, then uh DOM
purify becomes,
you know, it doesn't work effectively.
So, man, it is a hard problem to solve,
but I think we're going to continue
going back and forth as uh as W and Bug
Hunter and uh treating trading punches
in the street fight, right? You know.
>> Yes. Yes. Or we have to do our arm
wrestling.
>> Exactly. Yeah, dude. Right at the end.
Boom. Um I did want to mention one other
thing here which is going to be
interesting. I think that one of the
things I'm most excited about is uh for
the onset of hackbots is a WTF bypassing
bot.
>> Uh I think that's going to be really
interesting. Um and Kaido by the time
this uh episode airs or I'm gonna have
to cut this segment. We'll see. uh Kaido
uh will have released this thing called
shift agents where you can inside of
Kaido create your own hackbot of sorts
and and delegate a tabask. Yeah. You can
give it a task and you can give it a tab
in in replay right and then it will
modify replay and you can you know click
through it just like you normally do
forward forward back and see what things
it's tried
>> and then create things. Um, so what I
wanted to ask about that was like, and I
don't know, man, Ryan, you can you can
sit, you cannot answer this. I told you
I was gonna put the screws to you a
little bit on this podcast. What kind of
things do we need to have in our arsenal
a as hackers? What should we know about
bypassing WS? Um, we talked about
encoding already. Is there anything else
you can give us?
>> Oh, no. Uh, this may have to be uh when
we're in Vegas at a face toface get
together.
>> I don't know that that's a good I'm not
sure. Well, I mean most things are out
there.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
>> no, I I will say in general and it's not
an Okami thing.
>> Yeah.
>> Is
joining different
>> I think everybody knows Okami is the
biggest pain in the ass to bypass. Like
it is.
>> We hope so.
>> It's very hard. But go ahead.
>> Yeah. It it's when you're joining
multiple different techniques together
and you know if you go to like even Port
Swiggers
>> cheat sheet cross-ite scripting
>> it's like they have a lot of individual
things but if you start mixing and
matching um that's a challenge.
>> Um yeah I mean outside of that of course
then it's secrets we can't we can't take
you behind the the old powerful
>> I know it's in here somewhere. What room
where do you keep the wife the W bypass?
>> It's down the hall. I got to keep an eye
on Justin.
>> Dang it. you my badge. Got to have
access to that.
>> Yeah.
>> Um well, very very good, man. Very good.
Um
>> so I guess we talked a little bit about
what it would look like, you know, how
hackers often circumvent WS. Um but one
of the things we didn't touch on quite
as much is this this piece of ad AWS API
gateways and using stuff like um
Fireroxs
>> and stuff like that, you know, to get
around
>> these IP based restrictions. is that I
know that you have mentioned in the past
that
>> um AWS has this as a part of their terms
of service that that we shouldn't be we
shouldn't be using that um
what like what I want you to say to the
bug hunter is you know to do it or not
to do it right it kind kind of goes to
this whole this whole concept of like
bug bounty is supposed to be an
emulation of attackers and they're not
actively preventing us from using uh AWS
gateway way. Do you think it's it's
unethical for an ethical hacker to do
that?
>> That that's a good one. Um I think it's
tough when you know what the acceptable
use policy is and you choose to buy.
That's a personal decision.
>> So what you're saying we should cut this
segment. Is that what you're saying?
>> Uh so speaking in general for a second,
like you said, there's a couple tools,
right, that that can help to automate
some of this.
>> But part of the question is, okay, why
are you doing this? Well, it's the IP
blocking.
>> Mh.
>> And so you have to be able to distribute
whatever you want to do workloads and
come different IPs. So you're getting
around that problem.
>> So there are ways to do that that don't
violate acceptable use.
>> Um so another interesting side thing,
right? Okami had purchased Lenode a few
years back, right?
>> They have a lot of bug hunters on there
and a lot of people were using like
Axium and those kinds of tools.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh for a while I talked to the trust and
safety. It wasn't my doing. Everybody
said, "I'm just I'm on a a WebEx with
those folks and they said, "Hey, we have
to cut this because people were running
it to the hilt."
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And it was having network problems. So,
they disallowed Axium for a little
while, but
>> their customers say, "Hey, we're going
to go somewhere else. We'll go to a
different VPS." So, they worked with
Axiom uh project folks and said, and
there is a a document there says, "Hey,
everybody, if you're going to run this,
here's a way to put some bounds. Here's
a few flags that maybe people didn't
know about. You can still scan, but you
won't take down the network,
>> right?
>> Here's a a few flags that you didn't
know about clearly.
>> Can't read the docs. Um, so there's ways
to do all of that. Now, where it gets
interesting again is for me, I have to
deal with both thread actors and bug
hunters.
>> And thread actors are a pain. They have
DTPs that they do. Bug hunters, we've
joked, they're they're we have a
frennemy relationship, right? We are all
security researchers. You're not my
enemy.
>> But the interesting thing is when the
TTPs overlap
>> and what I was seeing is we see attack
traffic coming from Amazon API gateway
IPs.
>> Mh.
>> And the there's a lot of overlapping
topics here. But how would I know once I
investigate this is a bug hunter, right?
>> So I can start to look now if the
program
>> says you have to do request header
tagging and say hacker one handle. I can
look and say, "Okay, they're bug
hunters. Not a big deal."
>> The problem is we were seeing enough
traffic where there were no indications
that it was bug hunter traffic.
>> Yeah, a lot of people don't use those
headers.
>> Well, and then I said, "Okay, they might
not use the headers." But then I was
looking at what was being sent
>> and it was stuff that was more damaging
the SQL injection dropping tables and I
said, "This could be a regular
attacker."
>> Yeah.
>> Not bug hunter. So,
>> I have to initiate conversations with
security teams at do at at AWS.
Very similarly, we saw on Cloudflare
people setting up web workers. All they
were doing is open proxy and they would
funnel their traffic.
>> Oh jeez.
>> So I had to get with Cloudflare even
though competitors but there's security,
trust, safety.
>> So here's where it gets interesting
though like you said the the person
doing the activity and saying okay is
this acceptable use? Uh
>> am I going to get in trouble like all
that? It's a similar thing for the
companies I talk with because it's a
situation of if you're doing this but
you're paying your bill every month,
>> right?
>> Do they really care? Yeah. So, I don't
know. The mileage varies where sometimes
they say, "No, no, we're shutting this
down." And they do.
>> Other times they don't because you pay
for it.
>> But one other thing bug hunters should
think about too from a Lenode
perspective.
>> Yeah.
>> The trust and safety team. Uh sometimes
people will get access, spin stuff up,
scan who are not bug hunters, they're
thread actors, and they've using a
stolen credit card.
>> Yeah.
>> And quickly they figure it out and shut
it down, but they scan for a day.
>> You know what I mean? So keep that in
mind when you're doing what you're doing
as bug hunters. You're you're right next
to people who aren't.
>> Sometimes there's some friendly fire
repercussions. We are sorry.
>> Well, I I I like that. I like that
because it is frustrating, you know,
especially when you're an ethical
researcher. It's like, "No, I'm on your
team. Stop inhibiting me." But yeah,
especially when that infrastructure is
also being used negatively and and you
know, you're saying it is um it's a
difficult it's a difficult balance to to
strike. But yeah, I think I think if you
can use stuff like um like Axiom or
Shadow Clone or whatever, right,
>> and not break the uh the the terms of
service on a lot of these uh Yeah.
providers, then maybe that's maybe
that's for the best.
>> As much as I hate to say it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. What um I guess let me
ask you this. Has there been thought and
has Aami sort of pursued working with
the platforms to create an environment
where um hackers could either go through
a VPN or a proxy or something like that
and bypass the W to validate their proof
of concepts um you know and and kind of
working with the platform for that. um
to a certain degree yes I mean I've
we've talked I know offline a little bit
about this but
>> just brainstorming lots of different
ways to figure this out as we were
saying the normal mechanisms to allow a
commercial desk customer just aren't
there in this context
>> the IPs are rotating constantly
>> yeah so you need some way to validate if
you're coming directly through the W
product so uh there's some discussions I
will say they're early but talking about
part of the question is If you wanted to
do something like this, who registers
the bug hunter? Who gives a token? Who
manages? There's that question of who
could do that. But if something's
implemented, then it's a matter of Okami
making it an option for a customer to
opt into if they even wanted to do that.
>> Yeah.
>> But you would let them buy there. So,
yeah, we're brainstorming some ideas
because we know it's a pain point.
There's there's some there's some stuff
in this document here about using like
TLS fingerprints to try to figure out
I'm trying to think about how all that
would work. What is what is the vision
for that?
>> Well, again, this is me.
>> Yeah, this is just Ryan Ryan
brainstorming um and uh I don't think he
would care I said anything, but like I
pinged uh Benite and I was like, "Hey,
>> if we were to do something like this
because the question is how can we
validate somebody that's not an IP?"
>> Yeah. And there's tools out there that
let's say you're going through a proxy
that you can run that will funnel all
your traffic goes over then TLS
>> different tools where oh wait a second
in TLS there's all this different data
in there where you can have like a
comment field
>> maybe you put your hacker hand like
something there the end result is
certain parts of your TLS fingerprint
will change
>> and all of a sudden that becomes unique
to you
>> and so I mentioned saying that because
in in Optimize W product you can do a
bypass list based on a TLS signal.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> So we're trying to figure out low
friction.
>> Yeah. How do you make that simple for
the researcher and for the companies
that are implementing that?
>> So I don't know that we are at
brainstorming phase. So hopefully you're
saying well we're out in Vegas and we're
yeah
>> brainstorming with hackers and whatever.
Maybe there's other ideas, but any way
we can do this?
>> One of the other things that I kind of
thought of for this was attacking the
problem from the application layer and
saying, "Hey, okay, we've got a set of
um certificates that uh trusted
researchers have." And then we create
our our HTTP request and we, you know,
add an X AI researcher header with the
signature for the for that request.
Right.
>> Right. And and you know, that includes a
time stamp and stuff like that. So, it
can't be like vulnerable to replay
attacks, right?
>> And then we utilize that. It's not going
to be perfect because, you know, it's
not going to get us past all of the like
all of our tools aren't going to be able
to integrate that that signing structure
and stuff like that, but at least for
like Kaido and Burp,
>> you would be able to have an extension
that would
>> um allow you to get past Okami, right,
>> to to get at the target. Um,
>> well, most the CDM platforms are able to
do client certificate validations. So
>> yeah, it's it makes more sense to do it
at the TLS layer, I think.
>> Well, yeah, it just depends on how you
wanted to implement that. So it it is a
problem that should be solved.
>> We got to keep brainstorming, I guess.
>> Very tricky. Very tricky.
>> Um, so dude, you are presenting at Black
Hat this year with your daughter. Come
on, do some That's like dad goals right
there.
>> Absolutely.
>> Um, congrats Isabella on getting your uh
talk accepted. That's really awesome.
Congrats to you, Ryan. Um, you know, you
you've done some Unicode stuff last year
as well. Um, can you give us a teaser of
what Lost in Translation is going to
look like this year.
>> Um, yeah. So,
>> I guess by the time this has aired, what
it'll already be out, so don't give me a
teaser. Give me the give me the good
stuff.
>> Yeah, very true.
>> Um, yes, you'll be able to go, I think,
download our presentation. Yeah.
>> Um, yeah. So last year at Defcon Bugdown
village um it it was a higher level
concept of what are different ways where
back to this order of operation problem
if data
>> goes through some security checks and
then later it's changed in some way that
causes a problem
>> right so last year we talked about
different scenarios you have like
edgeside includes
>> that might change it on the way back out
yeah
>> um
>> uh there was the HTML entity decoding
which can split and you like there's all
sorts of different things so the one
that resonated though was things related
to Unicode.
>> Yeah.
>> So we said, "Okay, that's what was
interesting. Can we expand it a bit?" So
over the past year, we were trying to
gather stuff. And my daughter, I think,
had laughed at me before, like when
we're on, you know, socials or doing
whatever. And I said, "Oh, bookmark. Uh,
bookmark." She said, "What are you
doing?" I said, "Anytime I see cool
stuff on our our like feeds, I'm like,
"Oh, bookmark that for later." I come
back. So just to give kind of a quick
run through on on what this is kind of
from a agenda perspective. Um one thing
that's interesting is you have to start
with URL decoders
>> like before you even get to what the
character should be like in its regular
form or glyph or whatever. So URL
decoders can have different problems.
The first one is if it is not multibite
aware which you would think isn't it 20
25 what?
>> Yeah you think you'd think that that
would be solved already but really like
multibite I think a deep understanding
of unic code is pretty is pretty rare
and yeah I know I talked to I think you
probably listened to the episode with
Matias and where we where we uh talked
about this a little bit. So you know
lately it's been coming across you know
the pod a good bit that these multibite
sequences can be really um really
impactful.
>> Yeah. So what what was interesting as we
were going to prep the what do we show
people when we're talking about this?
>> Well, just fire up burp and go to
decoder.
>> Yeah,
>> it's not multi-aware.
>> you put in UTF8, you get emoji bake.
>> Yeah,
>> it's like ah. So we had to get a
different extension.
>> You get Oh, what did you say? Moji what?
>> Moji bake. That's what it's called.
>> What is emoji bake?
>> That is when data is translated in a way
that it was not encoded and you get
gibberish. It's called emoji bake.
>> Ah, okay.
>> I was going to say you're picking up on
the Japanese.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I'm like yeah bay yeah so I
I said that word to Isabella and same
thing she's like wait what is that and
so we were researching like that but
>> it has a name
>> so yeah in burp you have to use decoder
improved
>> it's got Java swing line and it under
properly decodes it understands UTF8
basically
>> so that's one thing and there's lots of
things that are not fully like say
multibite aware because technically
we're just saying really UTF8 normally
>> the other one is overong wrong encoding.
>> So, so when let me ask a question about
that. So, multibite sequences, that's
when you've got like um percent EF, uh
percent BC, and then something else,
right? Yep.
>> And it's got those those longer
sequences that that will create a
Unicode character.
>> Correct. Okay.
>> So, a great shout out, maybe it'll be in
the notes, Sonar Source. They do a lot
of great research,
>> but they have a tool. It's a UTF8 online
visualizer.
>> Yeah,
>> it is awesome. It's so fun. I've seen
that before and we've covered it on the
pod and I totally forgot about it and
then I I was having trouble visualizing
this in in the pod with Matias and like
four people messaged me and were like
you should use this like this. Yeah. Uh
very very cool piece of software they
built there.
>> Yeah. And it's great because it shows
you at the bottom the UTF8 encoded
bytes.
>> Yeah.
>> The next thing are the actual raw bytes
and then you have the Unicode code point
and the glyph.
>> Yeah.
>> So it depends on what layer you want to
look at. Uh but it it helps you to
understand that wait a second these
three individual bytes that are encoded
as percent 80% whatever they're all in
relation to each other
>> because there's one that's a leading
bite and then you have a continuation
>> bite bite. Yeah.
>> But it depends on what the character is
and what each bite is storing and things
like that. But yeah, if you emoji bake
it
>> and you just get crap.
>> Yeah. So what's interesting is from a
defender perspective, if we're going to
look at data and make a security
decision, if we emoji bake it, we're
screwed.
>> But the other thing is if the
application's moji baking it, that can
cause problems. So it depends. Oh
>> yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Because there were
scenarios and maybe get into this. Um
>> Oh, I guess that makes sense. One's a
you're perceiving it as a unicode
character, but they're perceiving it as
>> you know or Yeah. Okay. That's
interesting. If they treat each bite as
a individual asky character
>> and they ignore the leading bit, it's a
seven by bit asky,
>> then you can get a asky character and
two who knows what characters that may
be thrown out.
>> Yeah.
>> So when you think about uh control line
feed injections
>> with response splitting, that's where we
saw a crazy bug bounty report.
>> I want to say was that a report on X or
on Twitter back in the day? Do do Yeah.
by file descriptor, I think, was the guy
that that did it.
>> I don't remember the handle, but the one
I was looking at, um, it was Bug Bounty
vers Microsoft. Yeah.
>> Said, "How I got $6,000?"
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and we had to deal with this. I I
dealt with the very similar problem at
work when I first saw this. Yeah.
>> I said, "Wait a second. I know from a
defender, you're trying to do response,
you know, injection. You're trying to do
a set cookie.
>> You're sending these crazy Chinese
characters." Yeah.
>> But when it comes out of the app, it's
control line feeds. What the heck is
happening here? Now, on the one hand,
>> it could be a URL decoder issue, emoji
bake, where
>> it's only taking the lowest bite and did
it, but the other aspect that we
researched that's kind of a related
category is what we call unicode
truncation.
>> That's where even if the URL decoder is
multibite, you decode it, you get to
what the character is,
>> how's it going to use that character? Is
it going to put it in a database? Is it
going to put it in memory? M
>> and again most of our customers that
they're black boxes but we can tell that
they're doing URL decoding appropriately
but they took that character and all
they're doing is taking the least
significant bite
>> treating it as AS asy and it becomes an
asy character. So a lot of these control
line feed injections when you see those
on cheat sheets this is why they work
because the app is just saying nope
we're treating this as ASI.
>> Okay. So yeah. So there's there's
truncation. There's uh there's and then
there's also normalization and there's
things not actually parsing it as
multibite sequences.
>> Yep.
>> There's um what's the what's the other
one that Matias mentioned? Uh over uh
over long.
>> Yeah, that's a subcategory too of
>> it's it's a question in the RFC about
how you're supposed to do this. So, if
anybody by the time you're listening to
this, we're maybe at our talk.
>> Yeah.
>> That the real world analogy we have is a
a picture we got offline of an Amazon
box and you open it up, there's another
Amazon box and a bunch of packaging and
you're looking at it saying, "Why didn't
you just send me that box?"
>> Exactly.
>> It's the same thing. Overong encoding is
needless padding.
>> So, you have an ASKY character. It's a
single bite. Yeah,
>> you can send it that way. But you can
send it in two bytes if you wanted. But
that other bite, all it's doing is
saying I'm a leading bite, but I don't
have any data. The data are
>> just look at that guy.
>> Yeah. So yeah. So the question is what
do you do with that? Either you can
fully normalize it back to
>> ASKI,
>> which in my view is better
>> or you can say this is bad. I'm going to
block it. Mhm.
>> So the the one throwback I gave to my
daughter as we were prepping to this and
I said when I see this sequence of the
overlong I get a shiver in my and she
said why and I said because back in 2001
the nimdaworm came out and what the
nimda the nimdaworm what's the nimdaworm
>> so whoever named this was real crafty
yeah it's admin spelled backwards ah
>> so it's the nimdaworm and what it was
doing was propagating across Microsoft
environments
It would exploit systems through a bunch
of different protocols in different
ways, but one was through IIS server.
>> They overlong encoded dot dots and
slashes.
>> So the security check would fail
>> because it was overong, but then it
would get normalized after the fact and
then they could do command injection and
all sorts of stuff. So gosh, this
stuff's not new.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's still around.
>> It's been around for a while and it will
continue to be around because because
this unicode thing is tricky. It really
is. And there's a lot of uh there's you
know there's best fit mappings, there's
truncation, there's all sorts of things.
One of the things that I think is really
interesting also is is what you put in
here in the doc is the casing the casing
related problems, right? Yeah.
>> Uh can you tell us a little bit about
some of the gotchas where you know
characters may be different, you know,
and simply running like upper or lower
on something canact transform it uh in
these environments.
>> Yeah. like you were saying like
confusables and best fit mappings more
people are aware of that over time.
Yeah,
>> this is something too that I think as a
developer you're not thinking there's a
unic code component to this but there is
>> now each platform and language depending
on how you're doing upper and lower and
you can be doing upper I can't remember
full in Python I can't remember there's
different terms
>> but
when you think from a bug hunter
perspective oh here's some input what
type of an attack should I do here right
>> so this is something when you think
about like usernames
>> they don't want to have you log in as
like Justin@mail.com.
I log in as capital J Justin. Yeah. And
those are separate. No, no, they're the
same. So anytime you think we need to
normalize and not have a case sensitive
problem,
>> typically they would uppercase or
lowercase it. And when it does that,
there's case mapping in Unicode. So you
can put in a Unicode character. And this
was something that was very uh
interesting as well. It's kind of
related. It was one of the things we
talked about uh it was actually on
Nahome Con this year right the ATO puny
code stuff
>> y
>> as we were looking at this and we were
trying to generalize it and say well
>> could there be an uppercase casing
transform component not in this
particular case but in general maybe but
then this dovetales into collations and
databases
>> man
>> yeah so as we were researching that the
interesting thing again now is it's
unicode combining characters so when If
you think about you, let's say you have
an A character and it's got an accent
graph on it, right? Or unlots or like
whatever it might be.
>> Depending on the normalization that may
happen, they may do a decomposition and
say, "Okay, we understand what this
glyph is, but when we store it, we're
going to store it as ASKA
>> and an accent grab separately." Right?
>> Okay.
>> So, keep that in mind because with these
collations that databases may have, they
can have default flags. and we were
looking at my SQL because we actually
highlight the atto puny code example.
>> Interesting. Yeah.
>> So what it'll do is you pass that in
let's say with an a with an accent
character.
>> The default flags in my SQL is AI which
is accent insensitive. So even if you
pass something in that has an accent on
it, it ignores it. So now you just have
the base character.
>> No way. Yeah. So my SQL itself is doing
that conversion.
>> Yeah. It's part of the default. So if
you're in
>> it's a part of the default config. Oh my
gosh.
>> Yeah. And also the other flag is case
insensitive.
>> Ah
>> so case insensitive accent insensitive.
Now it depends on the collation.
>> Right. However, so if you're bug
hunting, who knows? They may have set
their own collation and they may be
handling stuff.
>> Okay. I'm sorry. I keep on saying
collation. I don't have a firm grip of
what collation is. What is a collation?
>> Uh yeah, it's 100 discre. Basically,
it's you're checking the equivalency of
two characters.
>> Okay. So in the basic SQL statement that
we did, it's just saying, oh, select in
quotes the unic code character A with
the accent
>> equals
in quotes asky character A. Okay.
>> And it's either returning a zero or one.
>> Oh, okay. Okay.
>> So are the are these the same character?
And when it says one, oh, they're the
same.
>> That's not the same. And then we show if
you change the collation when you do the
select and we changed it to be accent
sensitive, then it's at zero. No, no,
these don't match.
>> Dude, I'm so hyped for this talk right
now. This is going to be crazy.
>> Yeah, it was interesting as we were
looking at that because we want to
understand, wait, how did this actually
work?
>> Um,
>> there's so many layers to it as well,
right? Like, you know, there's the
there's the WAT layer, there's the
application layer, there's the database
layer, you know, there's the browser,
right? Like we were talking about, we we
saw a um this is only tangentally
related, but we saw an exploit come
across Google VRP the other day um that
got got um disclosed
>> uh that was uh taking advantage of um
liatures in the default font used in
your URL bar.
>> Nice.
>> So, you know, there was a Google
liature,
>> you know, to create the Google logo in
the font, you know, we covered it on the
pot. It was like now it's ringing the
bell. It was freaking beautiful, man. It
was it was lovely. Um, so there's so
many layers to this dude.
>> The one last thing because that's what
we were focusing on initially for
combining characters or or uh D
>> critics.
>> Dior critics. Yeah.
>> Um, the other thing which is interesting
for bug hunters.
>> Yeah.
>> Is think about the sources and syncs
again. If there's a sync where your data
is right before let's say a greater than
character. So you have like a text
input. Yeah. It's ending. What if you
only put the combining character as your
first character?
And so what we have here as an example,
there's code.
>> Dude, this is a dream. Please. Yes.
>> You can break context, right? So what
you can do is you send this Unicode
character which is a reverse full width
sold
or a full width sold depending on which
way you want it to go. Reverse.
>> Is it the one you have linked in the
dock here? This U038.
Oh my gosh.
then
>> it will combine and become a not greater
than symbol.
>> Now the key here though is this has to
happen server side. There needs to be
where the code that's going to be
rendered and generated for the web page
including your your um like whatever
input text it's wrapped in a
normalization
>> and they're adding your character in. So
is it semi-edge case? Maybe. Is it worth
check tooling? It's something to try you
know. Absolutely. And and I've also
thought about this many times and I I've
tried to make it work time and time
again in in um scenarios where you know
you need to get rid of something
following your your thing where I I'll
put like a um
>> I'll put a percent sign
>> there, right? And I'll try to like get
an amperand like like say I need to get
rid of a um
>> a
query parameter that is appended after
my specific thing, right? I'll put like
a a percent sign in there and then it
becomes percent amperand, you know, the
first character of the the query query
parameter. Right. Right. And then that's
an invalid, you know, URL decoding. So
then it freaks out and sometimes it does
weird stuff.
>> Yeah. You know, I don't know how to
decode this.
>> Yeah. Exactly. So, this is another thing
that we can try with that because I'
i've always been like, "Ah, there's got
to be something that I can do to affect
post, you know, because obviously the
the ideal situation is you've got like a
like a a hashtag or something like that
and you can turn it into the fragment or
whatever, right?
>> But you don't always have that. And so
all of the any primitive like this that
could potentially allow you to affect
>> previously hard-coded text that follows
your input,
>> right?
>> That's
>> so interesting, man. breaking context,
right? Um
>> frick, I love this. So, oh my gosh,
>> what we were doing in prepping
>> Oh my gosh.
>> for the talk and doing the research
>> um is to update tooling, right? We want
to give back and you know, let people
use this. So, um I've worked with James
Kettle. So, Active Scan Plus+ for Burp
users.
>> Uh we already have some poll requests in
there. We're making some more. But
basically the concept is and you can
adapt this to other tooling.
>> Yeah. Yeah. is if you're checking for
this behavior, it's figure out all
right, are we talking about confusables?
Do we want to see if there's any
normalization? Do we want to check for
bite trunk? Like what are we checking
for? And essentially, you get a prefix
and a suffix that are random strings.
Send whatever character you want in
between because then the random strings
tell you where it is in the the return.
>> Yep.
>> And you're seeing if it changes in the
way that you want it,
>> if it's transformed.
>> Yeah. So for example, if you want to see
if it does any normalization, you can
send the unic code Kelvin sign.
>> It normalizes under all four
normalizations. So then you know it's
doing something.
>> That's what I need to know. Okay.
Unicorn unicorn. Unicode Kelvin. Dang
it, guys. Do not make a meme in the
freaking Discord about unicorn. Please
t-shirt,
>> dude. Shut up, Ryan.
>> Uh the Unicode Kelvin sign. Okay. I
think I've seen this before because I
think there was a
>> they called it special K. Yes,
>> the special K polygon.
>> Exactly. That's the one. And I I believe
um the first time I was exposed to this
actually was um Yes, we hacks bit K
researcher um showed me some really cool
transformations in JavaScript. I think
that use that that K, right? Where you
can lowercase it and it goes to like a a
normal ASI lowercase K.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'm like, oh my gosh, that's crazy.
>> That's the same concept. So, you can
check for everything like we have the
other example for Unicode truncation. We
send a Chinese character. Yeah.
>> And if it comes back in between your
prefix and suffic as a left curly
bracket,
>> maybe you want to try some serverside
template injection. Like there's
different checks to do. So there should
be some tools out by the time our talk's
out.
>> All right. Wow. Definitely interesting
stuff there. Uh going to be on the
lookout for that talk. Um I'm glad I get
a little insight into it now. This is
good. This is good. I got to start
adapting some of this uh this tooling
for Kaido.
>> Um y
>> very nice, man. I think I think this
last bit about you the combining
characters is really intriguing to me in
my brain. I can feel it in my brain that
that I need to try to figure out what
combinations those are there are there.
>> Um I'm sure that's in your talk. I'm
excited to see it, man.
>> Y
>> um let's let's uh we've only got a
couple more things here. Uh you
mentioned, you know, active scan. Um we
talked a little bit about recolapse
before, right? where uh that's really
helpful for normalization tables and and
creating those kind of vulnerabilities
um fighting normalization
vulnerabilities. What what um you
mentioned SSO, you mentioned uh you know
usernames and stuff like that. What kind
of places do you see this most being uh
effective for the bug hunters? You know,
and and I guess it affects definitely
things like cross-ite scripting, you
know, normalization, but also you've got
critical impact with arbitrary account
takeover if normalization is happening
>> across SSO signin.
>> Yeah. So, I think some of these overlap
with the discussion about like
>> what are good vulnerabilities that WAP
is great at identifying.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So the atto stuff again got a
different product to help you account
takeovers. Yeah,
>> that's not like an injection. It's a
different scenario.
>> Um most of what I've seen when we get
tickets and we have to triage
>> it's around all of the um well SSRF
>> because enclosed alpha numeric
>> okay
>> those get normalized. There's a unic
code or an IDNA element processing there
with the with the URLs that does some
normalization. um control line feed
injections, okay? And then cross- sight
scripting. Those are the top three.
>> Those are the top three
>> that we see not only trying because we
see people try all sorts of crazy stuff
with the tools, right? And now you got
all these AI agents. It's cheap to test.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> But we have to weed out that and say
what are the things actually show impact
work.
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> And apps do crazy stuff.
>> Oh yeah.
>> And how they're transforming data. So,
we've seen examples where it's
confusables, it's casing. Haven't seen
any combining characters yet.
>> Keeping my eye out. Uh, but th those are
the big ones. And then it's like, well,
okay, why is it happening? And then
that's usually part of our triage.
>> Figure out what is going on.
>> Access, XSS, CRLF,
>> and SSRF.
>> SSRF. And then we've got those sort of
normalization attacks on SSO and
usernames.
>> Uh, yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. If it's normalizing.
>> All right. We'll uh we'll we'll give it
a shot. We'll see what we can find. I
definitely think the combining
characters research that you've done and
especially the I mean the the coalition
stuff for sure, but the um the combining
character stuff definitely has a lot of
potential. I think that will result in
some bugs.
>> I got to get some of those uh you know
into my um normal testing routine. You
know,
>> get them in your tooling.
>> Yeah. Um the last thing that we had
really on the list here is CSPs. Um,
and I think you have a very interesting
little piece here about how CSPs can
sometimes be implemented at the the WAT
level, right? You know, um, can you talk
about the pros and cons of implementing
CSP there and what bug hunters need to
know about that?
>> Yeah. Um,
whether it's a a quote unquote WFT or
just something that's an intermediary
that's upcreen from the app, right?
Yeah.
>> Um, some customers find that attractive
because maybe not every app stack they
have that can quickly, oh, you're doing
CSP like that's built into some apps,
right? It's easy to do.
>> Other ones it's not. And you want to
have a centralized place to have your
policies.
>> So, from an architecture perspective, it
makes sense for me when I work. Keep
hitting this thing. You're good.
>> Uh, when I work with customers who want
to do this, it's a question of what are
you trying to achieve with CSP,
>> right? What order do you implement these
in? And then where is it where you
probably want to do that at what we call
origin that's the customer application.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so anytime you're getting into we
want to
>> na
>> data to say obviously oh no this is
secure or hashing or anything like that
that really should be done at origin.
>> Yeah.
>> But other stuff is easy and fine. You
can push that where we say downstream to
us and then we'll send it out to the
client. So there's advantages depending
what they want to do with their policy.
What where this gets interesting is if
you have that intermediary
and it's autoning data originating from
the app, imagine right in the inline
cross-ey scripting.
>> Um, so yeah, I've I ran into this with
testing with some other thirdparty
security products that were doing this.
Yeah. as a customer was evaluating and I
kind of pointed this out because I was
able to do reflected XSS and it
autonounced it for me and I said I don't
think this is the best uh idea.
>> That's very interesting. Yeah, stored
XSS reflected XSS. I guess really what
that auton feature would be intended to
stop is is DOM XSS, right? Because
that's the only scenario where that's
really going to become handy. But
>> yeah, the the only kind of reference I
will make here again name dropping
>> that uh XSS doctor, right? And he's
doing all this cool stuff. Exactly.
>> My boy XSS doctor.
>> So we were chatting on Discord a little
bit and this was coming up and we were
just going over stuff and he had made a
comment about in general like CSP ways
to bypass it and generally saying oh
like if I see a non it's like is it
worth my time
>> to try and do because they're nonsing
it. Yeah. And so I just made that
comment. I said just because you see a
knots test.
>> Yeah,
>> it may be worth now are they in this
scenario? Maybe not, but they might be.
And then the non does not matter. It'll
auto not. So it's something again from a
tooling perspective. Maybe you could
test a few things and see. Yeah, I
wouldn't just give up on that.
>> Yeah, because it it may just be autoning
it. you might be considering it a part
or there could be some like I don't even
know if it's middleware you know
something you backend
backside wear I don't know you know that
that after everything's done it's going
back through and and and nonsing it uh
so there's lots of ways that that
attackers input could get nons in those
sort of situations.
>> Yep.
>> Wow. Very interesting stuff. And then
and then um you also you know one of the
things that uh you kind of have access
to with Okami is the perspective of
looking at these CSP violation reports.
>> Yeah.
>> Um what what kind of juicy stuff have
you found in those? and and uh I always
thought that that's a really cool vector
because if you were able even as an
attacker to inject into that you know
CSP reporting environment you can
trigger a a CSP violation and then you
know get data out that way. So there's
lots of cool tricks.
>> Yeah. Um right so we talked about the
scenario of if they wanted Okami to add
the CSP policies which we can y
>> then if you want to do any sort of
reporting to beaconing right
>> you can send that wherever you want it
doesn't have to be back to us or
whatever but um some customers opt to
have it come through us
>> and they can have us actually act as
like a CSP report endpoint and then they
can actually see stuff
>> interesting
>> or it goes all the way through but with
that we had to talk with them and say
Okay, well then when that's coming
through, you don't want have to block it
>> like just come on through and then they
have a reporting that's back behind us,
right? So it's an architectural
question. Now what's interesting what
you were just saying is I can look at
all sorts of CSP reports and if you're
familiar with what those reports look
like in the JSON different uh you know
policy things and it so I'm interested
in of course like samples and I said
report sample uh what was the blocked
URI there's a few things I go and look
at and there's interesting stuff that
you can see that people are trying to
beacon or what are they trying a new
technique whatever it might be what's
also funny though is exactly what you
just said all this tooling will take
anything and every input and whatever
and inject everywhere. It's inject
everything. And so I'll be looking at
something that oh what was the original
CSP policy cross-ite scripting tag.
They're just they're trying to anything.
You know what I mean? Because oh
>> maybe it'll pop somewhere. So that's
part of weeding out. It's like that's
bogus. That's just an attacker.
>> Yeah.
>> Futing around with the report JSON
coming back. So it's noise.
>> Yeah. Well, sometimes sometimes you know
those logs can end up I mean we talked
about a blind XSS scenario before. those
those can go into like janky backend
systems where they process it and
>> that's why blindness is so crazy. Yeah,
exactly. Exactly. Um so there's always
that that impact there as well. Very
very interesting. One one thing you said
before that I didn't have on the list,
but I do want to circle uh circle back
to is um
>> one of the first sort of interactions
that I had with a WAF as a as a hunter
was trying to bypass a WF uh via
locating the origin server. Um how often
do you see that misconfiguration in in
clients, you know, like where they're
not just whitelisting communication with
Okami, right?
>> Or something changes. Is that and and I
guess
>> I don't know. My question that I want to
ask is like how can I find the freaking
Origin server, but I don't know if
you're gonna be able to give me much
with that.
>> Uh not really. Mainly I I'll plead that
that's not my area of expertise. That's
a platform.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Get off the hook on that one. Um
>> that it is in a sense now it's supposed
to be a typical onboarding.
>> Yeah.
>> That you talk with a customer because we
have a lot of customers that are only on
performance.
>> Yeah. They want us as a CDN.
>> Yeah.
>> Reminding it. So, okay, fine.
>> Yeah. We don't even think about that as
hackers, you know, because we're like, I
got my W. But it's, you know, originally
it was a CDN, right?
>> Serves a purpose. Makes everything
faster. So,
>> yeah. Yeah. Uh, but security side of the
house, that's a discussion when there's
onboarding and to say, look, if you
don't want people to reach your origin
and get around the edge network, then
you have to figure out how to configure
that. Um, so they know about it. Now
question is okay why wasn't it
implemented? Um sometimes it's hard you
know you have to configure network
firewalls to figure out how to talk with
the edge systems
>> and make sure that they're always set up
properly right
>> um
>> and sometimes I guess that that doesn't
happen or things change. There's also
scenarios where
typically the edge network to make
everything faster it knows where servers
are that are geographically close to you
and all of that. So, you know, I again,
I don't work on that side of of the
operations and working with customers on
configuring, but if you only configured
it to work with certain ai servers
because they're in your region,
>> but then somebody goes through a
different one and you're just not
restricting.
>> I I don't know. Um, but yeah, being able
to bypass that, um, it it's an issue.
So, that's why we tell customers, no,
no, if you want this, we call it sight
shield.
>> You got to configure sight shield to say
we only talk, you know, with a now
>> directly. Yeah. The other scenario there
is you were thinking typically, oh, I'm
a hacker. I'm doing web application
attacks.
>> Um, there's also the issue of denial of
service.
>> Yeah.
>> That if they know the origin and go
directly to it. Now, in this case,
>> if they find an IP, they can still slam
it. Now, from an application, yeah, you
can't actually get in to do what you
wanted, but if they're just wanting to
flood, they can do that anyway. So,
again, there's different DOS scenarios
>> where we can front end and we have a
whole different system for doing that.
But um yeah, but that's been an issue
with any CDN W. I've seen tools out
there with like Cloudflare trying to
find
>> if you can find the original source IP
before they onboarded, that's the issue.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> So,
>> and and that's often in the DNS history,
you know, you can go back and look
before they onboarded their WFT. You
know, you can say, "Oh, where was that
IP?" Oh, it's still there.
>> Yeah. Internet never forgets.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. Um
>> uh Okay. I I said last thing, but I I
did come up with one more thing. Um, one
of the, you know, by nature of these
these WFTs, it's important that
it's necessary that you have to be able
to have some routes that you hit that
return data from the W rather than from
the actual origin, you know, something
to do like your bot check and stuff like
that. um that has become uh very
interesting attack surface uh for
attackers and I've spent a good amount
of time looking at um you know the SLC
CDNCGI
uh endpoints and stuff like that right
okay
>> um
>> I guess
>> what what is your your and this once
again this might be a product question
rather than you know the researcher side
which is kind of where you're at right
>> but um
>> running a bug bounty program yourself
right you
that I imagine is very high value attack
surface to you and it is uh would it
would it be possible maybe for us to get
some additional introspection into what
those endpoints are exposed on every on
every host?
>> Yeah, good question. Um well it is
important one thing that you just
mentioned that uh Okami does have a bug
bounty program right now it's scoped
just for the platform.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh but also Lenode had a long
>> Yeah. Excellent program. I approached
them. Yeah. So that's within scope of
what we're doing as well. Um so I don't
know that's a good question to fit. It's
a scoping question. Yeah. Right. We set
up also a sandboxed environment
>> that has different origin setups with
different stacks and also from more from
the protocol perspective that we want to
have uh engine X, Apache, Node.js, but
we have a whole system set up where you
can test and stuff echoes back and so
you can see what's happening.
>> That's interesting. um a a a hat tip uh
to James Kettle who's doing his his
research. You know, I we talked I
triaged his bone. He found that he's
talking about a black hat. Yeah.
>> Um so we have an area set up for this
which will help
>> to identify these types of situations
and gives you back some debugging
information to see exactly what made it
to origin, how did it change, how's it
coming back. Um, so it's not full-blown.
It is more of a product question on all
these different things that may
potentially have problems, but we're
looking to expand the scope.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
>> so the W currently is not in scope
>> like like if if we find vulnerabilities
um let's say on those endpoints that
need to be exposed,
>> right?
>> Uh,
you know that that are under a
customer's domain but are actually, you
know, AAI code, right?
>> Uh, those are currently not in scope.
>> Correct.
>> Rats. Okay.
>> It's it's a product question now. I am
working to get it within scope.
>> Yeah.
>> Part of the question is, okay, what
scope do you put around WTF?
>> Right.
>> Um
>> Yeah. Because there are some programs
that'll just be like, all right, here's
$25 per, you know, WFT bypass,
>> high volume, low value.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh we don't really want to get in that
game because when
>> Yeah.
>> part of when you think about the
day-to-day business of WFT, and yes, a
bit of whack-a-ole with some of the
detections, that's day-to-day business.
That's not something we deem as a like
evasion.
>> And some of this is internal
terminology. And I'm not sure maybe this
is something that I just use, but uh the
way I look at these are the day-to-day
stuff like that where oh that's an
interesting cross-hat scripting vector.
Okay, we need to catch that. That's a
bypass.
>> Evasion is something deeper in the
platform, protocol, processing. And the
way I say it is if my team can't fix it,
it's an evasion because we have to get
with engineers.
>> Ah,
>> whole different scope. and timelines and
so we don't want to get into the
bounties for bypass. That's
>> maybe we'll do some specials. I've seen
that before like hey for the next
>> whatever here send us
>> give us cool techniques.
>> Yeah. But right now it's it's focusing
more on on lower level
>> kind of protocol bypassing kind of.
>> That's that's fun research though. It's
a good research target. So um
>> glad you guys are running a program on
that.
>> Um one other thing I'll mention actually
this is going to come out I guess after
we're in Vegas. Um the current state of
the program, right? We had it private
for a while.
>> Now it's not private. It's on Hacker
One. You can find our page.
>> Um but it was invite for a while.
>> But now anybody who kind of asks,
>> we haven't turned anybody away. Like if
you say, "Hey, can I come to your
program?" We'll just let you in. And
then there's a little different
information where it gives you about our
sandbox and you do all that stuff. So we
are right on the fence to being
full-blown
>> public
>> public. We're working our way over that
fence. Um but anyways, I plan when I'm
in Vegas talking with people to let them
know.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so if you're talking with people and
they say Okamic say, "Oh, you can ask to
join the program. They can join."
>> Heck yeah, dude. I'm excited for that. I
think that'll be great. I think it's
really important for for these types of
software to have, you know, bug bounty
programs. And I know a public program is
a big step um and you got to deal with a
lot of uh you know, reported flux and
stuff like that, but
>> yeah, it's a bandwidth issue.
>> Yeah, absolutely, man. Well, uh,
whenever you guys go public, let me
know. I I'll give you a shout out. I owe
you one for for coming on the pod and
for showing me a good time up here
today. So,
>> absolutely pleasure,
>> dude. Thank you so much, man. Appreciate
it.
>> We got Hold on. Yeah, we got for the end
of the for the end of the episode. Let
me get the uh Hold on. Uh All right.
Well, we'll we'll call it a wrap there.
Oh, you guys can see. Um here we go.
This is going to be the thumbnail right
here. Yeah. Three, two, one.
>> Nice. Very good. All right. Thanks, man.
Great episode. And that's a wrap on this
episode of Critical Thinking. Thanks so
much for watching to the end, y'all. If
you want more critical thinking content,
uh, or if you want to support the show,
head over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.